<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Invoker</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="bully_body">
        "Bullying has become such a hot buzzword in our society these days that the mere mention of"
        " it can instantly trigger panic in the heart of the most experienced parent. So before "
        "you have a conversation with your child about bullying, know this: Not all hurtful "
        "behavior is bullying.\n\n"
        "Help Your Child Understand What Bullying Is . . . and Isn’t\n\n"
        "Bullying is comprised of three key elements: an intent to harm, a power imbalance, and "
        "repeated acts or threats of aggressive behavior. Kids who bully are consciously choosing "
        "to be cruel, with no sense of regret or remors, even when the targets of bullying show or "
        "express their hurt or tell the aggressors to stop. Sometimes they're hurting too, thinking"
        " that hurting someone else can stop their pain.\n\n"
        "I love how this one school I visited in Wisconsin helped their school community - "
        "students, teachers, and parents - understand the different tiers of hurtful behavior:\n\n"
        "When someone says or does something unintentionally hurtful and they do it once, that’s "
        "RUDE.\n\n"
        "When someone says or does something intentionally hurtful and they do it once, that’s "
        "MEAN.\n\n"
        "When someone says or does something intentionally hurtful and they keep doing it, even "
        "when you tell them to stop or show them that you’re upset, that’s BULLYING.\n\n"
        "When a child is mean to multiple people or publicly posts a hurtful comment online that "
        "can be viewed by many, they are creating a repeated pattern of meanness, which can cross "
        "the line into bullying. Those who bully often lack empathy, the ability to know what it "
        "feels like to be in someone else’s shoes and to have compassion for his/her pain and "
        "suffering. The more empathy and compassion we can instill in our children, the less room "
        "there will be in their hearts for contempt and disregard for others.\n\n"
        "Most Kids Aren’t Cruel—Offline or Online\n\n"
        "Numerous Internet safety advocates and experts report that most youth aren’t bullying "
        "their peers. That’s not to say that bullying isn’t a significant issue. The minority of "
        "kids who are bullying can cause real harm to both the targets of bullying AND the many "
        "bystanders who witness the bullying.\n\n"
        "Because kids tend to do what they believe the majority of their peers do, it’s important "
        "to share with your children this truth: Most youth are decent, caring, and responsible "
        "when it comes to how they treat others. Let your teens know that you expect no less from "
        "them. And if they do witness bullying, encourage them to report the abuse to an adult they"
        " trust or, if online, to the service provider or through the social network’s reporting "
        "system. Also encourage them to reach out and comfort the kid who is being bullied.\n\n"
        "Turning Kids’ Mistakes into Teachable Moments\n\n"
        "Let’s face it: our kids are going to make mistakes. Our job as caring parents is to make "
        "sure our kids don’t keep repeating those mistakes so they can move forward in positive, "
        "healthy ways. We do this by being good role models ourselves in how we treat those we "
        "encounter in life. We also need to hold our children accountable for their hurtful "
        "behaviors. You don’t want your kids to just say, Sorry. Have them SHOW they’re sorry by "
        "making up for the hurt they have caused others.\n\n"
        "Emphasize the Importance of Respecting Others’ Differences\n\n"
        "Remind your child that every person has value. While we all may not agree with others’ "
        "opinions, while we all may not end up being friends, we all deserve to have our presence "
        "acknowledged and to be treated in a civil and respectful manner.\n\n"
        "The reality is that we aren’t going to get rid of all the hurt in our kids’ world. What "
        "we can do is raise more emotionally resilient kids who have the tools and strength to get "
        "through the hurt, while the caring adults (teachers, school administrators, parents, and "
        "care givers) and kids in their lives work together to effectively address and prevent peer"
        " cruelty."
    </string>

    <string name="drug_body">
        "Parents matter. You are your child's most important role model and their best defence "
        "against drug use.\n\n"
        "By talking openly with your teen about drugs, you can strengthen your relationship with "
        "them. Once you have built a strong relationship, communication will be easier.\n\n"
        "When parents and teens disagree they sometimes drift away from each other. As hard as it "
        "may be, it is very important that you keep the lines of communication open.\n\n"
        "Your teen's point of view is very important.\n\n"
        "Most teens are happy with their relationship with their parents. However, many teens "
        "think their parents are not always there when they need them.\n\n"
        "As teens grow they need to be able to speak their mind. This may create conflict and "
        "during this time, you may think that your teen is not listening to you even though they "
        "really are.\n\n"
        "Remember that when your teen talks back and argues with you, it does not mean they are "
        "rejecting you. In fact, the opposite may actually be true. By asserting their "
        "independence, your teen is building a stronger and more positive relationship with you.\n\n"
        "Many teens don't want to talk just about drugs; they would also like to talk about other "
        "things such as adulthood and puberty, school issues and friendships.\n\n"
        "Beyond a strong relationship and open communication with parents, there are other "
        "important factors that can decrease or increase the chances that teens may experiment "
        "with drugs.\n\n"
        "Some of the key factors that can help your teen make the right choices include:\n\n"
        "- a strong family attachment\n"
        "- positive involvement in the community\n"
        "- connection at school\n"
        "- religious and spiritual beliefs\n"
        "- social skills\n"
        "- positive friendships\n\n"
        "Some of the key factors that can increase the chances that your child may experiment with "
        "drugs are:\n\n"
        "- low self-esteem\n"
        "- drug use by friends\n"
        "- peer pressure\n"
        "- conflict in families\n"
        "- poor grades\n"
        "- lack of connection at school\n\n"
        "Empower your teen. Help them resist drug use by:\n\n"
        "- nurturing their self-confidence and intelligence;\n"
        "- creating a sense of hope and optimism;\n"
        "- ensuring they grow up in a safe environment and are involved in extracurricular "
        "activities; and,\n"
        "- making sure they have the community support that they need.\n\n"
        "When talking with your teenager about drugs, here are a few tips to keep in mind.\n\n"
        "Think first. Act second. Try to stay clear and focused and don't get too emotional. Keep "
        "an open mind.\n\n"
        "Keep an eye on your teen's behaviour. Ask them everyday what they are doing and don't be "
        "afraid to set limits such as curfews.\n\n"
        "Encourage your teen to work with you to set boundaries, but don't be afraid to adopt a "
        "strong position when you need to.\n\n"
        "Don't be afraid to enforce the boundaries you have set. Let your teen know that you are "
        "setting boundaries because you care for them and want only the best for them.\n\n"
        "Find ways to ensure that your teen believes what you say and trusts you.\n\n"
        "Talk regularly and talk often. Many "mini-conversations" about drugs are better than long "
        "boring lectures.\n\n"
        "When talking with your teen, think about their point of view and listen respectfully to "
        "what they have to say.\n\n"
        "Keep the conversation positive and upbeat rather than waiting for an opportunity to "
        "criticize your teen for bad behaviour.\n\n"
        "Take advantage of teachable moments to discuss drug use with your teen. Teachable "
        "moments can happen while driving in the car, at the dinner table while discussing a "
        "situation at school or a current event in the news.\n\n"
        "Eat dinner together as often as possible. The family dinner provides one effective way to "
        "strengthen your communication with your teen.\n\n"
        "Help your teen develop sound reasoning skills and encourage conversations and the open "
        "exchange of ideas and feelings.\n\n"
        "Focus on messages about how drug use affects sports performance, health and appearance. "
        "These messages have more impact because this age group is more affected by peer pressure, "
        "doubt and feeling insecure. Teens like to feel like they belong, that they look and act "
        "like their friends.\n\n"
        "Have a two-way conversation with your teen. Listen to them and respect their opinion. "
        "Provide your teen with information that is meaningful and balanced, without emotion or "
        "drama so that they feel empowered to make healthy choices about drugs.\n\n"
        "Remember to keep the lines of communication open with your teen. Start early and get ahead"
        " of the drug questions. Teens should learn about drugs from their parents first. Be clear "
        "on where you stand about drugs. You are their most important role model and their best "
        "defence against drug use."
    </string>

    <string name="rel_body">
        "It happened. You knew it would, but you didn’t think it would happen so quickly. In spite "
        "of any hope you had of slowing down the clock, you woke up one day to find that your child"
        " is not so childlike anymore. Suddenly, hormones are raging, romantic feelings are "
        "developing, and, of course, it doesn’t stop there. Before you know it, your teen may be "
        "entering the dating world.\n\n"
        "For many, raising a teenager is the most intimidating chapter of parenthood. Discipline "
        "becomes increasingly difficult and may feel impossible to maintain. It’s tough to know "
        "when to set rules and when to give freedom, when to bend and when to stand firm, when to "
        "intervene and when to let live.\n\n"
        "Communication is often one of the trickiest minefields to navigate. It’s a struggle to "
        "know what to say, when to say it, and how to say it. These conversations and decisions "
        "only become more challenging when the time comes for your teen to start dating.\n\n"
        "If you are a parent to a blossoming teen, consider discussing these crucial aspects of "
        "relationships with your child before they enter into a relationship:\n\n"
        "1. Define a Healthy Relationship\n\n"
        "Be sure to teach your teen about the foundations of a healthy relationship. Explain that a"
        " healthy relationship comes from respect, mutual understanding, trust, honesty, "
        "communication, and support.\n\n"
        "A relationship should consist of healthy boundaries that are established and respected by "
        "both partners equally. A good partner will accept you as you are, support your personal "
        "choices, and praise you for your achievements. A healthy relationship also allows both "
        "partners to maintain outside interests and friendships, and does not hinder the personal "
        "freedom of either partner.\n\n"
        "2. Describe the Different Types of Abuse and Associated Warning Signs\n\n"
        "There are many different types of abuse your teen should be aware of before entering into "
        "a relationship. These include physical, emotional, sexual, financial, and digital abuse, "
        "as well as stalking.\n\n"
        "Physical abuse occurs when a person uses physical force to harm another, but need not "
        "result in visible injuries to qualify. Hitting, kicking, pushing, biting, choking, and "
        "using weapons are all forms of physical abuse.\n\n"
        "Emotional abuse can take the form of insults, humiliation, degradation, manipulation, and "
        "intimidation. Emotional abuse can involve forced isolation, coercion, or use of fear or "
        "guilt to control or belittle.\n\n"
        "Sexual abuse involves any act that directly or indirectly impacts a person’s ability to "
        "control their own sexual activity and the conditions surrounding it. It can take many "
        "forms, including forced sexual activity, using other means of abuse to pressure one into "
        "an activity, and restricting access to condoms or birth control.\n\n"
        "Financial abuse is a form of emotional abuse that uses money or material items as a means "
        "of power and control over another person.\n\n"
        "Digital abuse is any form of emotional abuse using technology. A person may use social "
        "media, texting, or other technological means to intimidate, manipulate, harass, or bully "
        "someone.\n\n"
        "Stalking is persistent harassment, monitoring, following, or watching of another person. "
        "These behaviors can be difficult for teens to recognize as abuse, as they may sometimes "
        "see it as flattering or believe the other person is engaging in such behaviors only out of"
        " love.\n\n"
        "3. Explain the Differences between Lust, Infatuation, and Love\n\n"
        "Distinguishing between infatuation and love can be difficult for many adults; imagine how "
        "complicated it can be for a teenager who is experiencing many new feelings for the first "
        "time. Take a moment to explain to your teen that attraction and desire are physiological "
        "responses that can occur separately from emotions.\n\n"
        "Make sure he or she understands that infatuation is not the same as love. Infatuation may "
        "give us butterflies, goose bumps, and that “can’t eat, can’t sleep” type of feeling, but "
        "it isn’t the same as love. Love takes time to grow, whereas infatuation may happen almost "
        "instantly.\n\n"
        "4. Talk Realistically about Sex\n\n"
        "While it may be tempting to skip this conversation, it’s in everyone’s best interests to "
        "talk to your teen about sex. Ask yourself whether you want your teen to hear this "
        "information from you or someone else.\n\n"
        "Be sure to get your teen’s point of view and let your teen hear all sides from you. "
        "Discuss the pros and cons of sex honestly. Talk about questions of ethics, values, and "
        "responsibilities associated with personal or religious beliefs.\n\n"
        "5. Set Expectations and Boundaries\n\n"
        "It is important to set expectations and boundaries you have now regarding your teen dating"
        " rather than defining them through confrontation later. Let your teen know any rules you "
        "may have, such as curfews, restrictions on who or how they date, who will pay for dates, "
        "and any other stipulations you might have. Give your teen an opportunity to contribute to "
        "the discussion, which can help foster trust.\n\n"
        "6. Offer Your Support\n\n"
        "Be sure to let your teen know you support him or her in the dating process. Tell your teen"
        " you can drop off or pick up him or her, lend a compassionate and supportive ear when "
        "necessary, or help acquire birth control if that fits with your parenting and personal "
        "philosophies. However you intend to support your teen, make sure they know that you are "
        "available.\n\n"
        "7. Use Gender-Inclusive Language that Remains Neutral to Sexual Orientation\n\n"
        "When you open the discussion with your teen about relationships and sexuality, consider "
        "using gender-inclusive language that remains neutral to sexual orientation. For example, "
        "you might say something like, “Are you interested in finding a partner?” rather than "
        "automatically assuming your teen’s sexuality. Deliver this language with genuine openness "
        "and love.\n\n"
        "By opening up the possibility of being attracted to any gender right away, you will not "
        "only make it easier for your teen to be open with you about their sexual orientation, but "
        "you’ll likely make your teen feel more comfortable with their identity, regardless of who "
        "your teen chooses to date.\n\n"
        "8. Be Respectful\n\n"
        "Most importantly, be respectful when talking to your teen about dating and relationships. "
        "If you communicate with your teen in a gentle, nonobtrusive manner that respects their "
        "individuality, opinions, and beliefs, then your teen will be much more likely to do the "
        "same for you. This helps to create a healthy and open line of communication between you "
        "and your child and ultimately could improve your teen’s self-esteem.\n\n"
        "9. Know When to Ask for Outside Help\n\n"
        "There is help available if you’re struggling to talk to your teen about dating and "
        "sexuality. In addition to our advice, there are numerous resources available online to "
        "help you start a constructive conversation. Additionally, if your teen is experiencing "
        "relationship problems and/or your talks about relationships aren’t going well, consider "
        "finding a family therapist who can help mediate the conversations and promote emotional "
        "intelligence and healthy behaviors. Teaching your kids what it means to be in a healthy "
        "relationship is simply too important of a message to leave to chance and may even save "
        "their someday."
    </string>

    <string name="sex_body">
        "What’s it all about?\n\n"
        "One of the passages of adolescence is the development and understanding of sexuality. This"
        " includes understanding one’s body, gender identity, sexual orientation, and values about "
        "sexual activity. During adolescence, many teens begin to explore their sexuality. For all "
        "teens, this is a challenging transition. But for teens who are questioning their sexual "
        "orientation, or who identify as being gay, lesbian, bisexual or transgender, this can be a"
        " very lonely, difficult and threatening transition. It can also be a difficult time for "
        "parents, who may have fears and questions of their own. It is crucial for teens to get "
        "support and understanding from their peers, parents and other adults when they have "
        "questions about sexual orientation.\n\n"
        "Why Does It Matter?\n\n"
        "It is a matter of emotional health, physical health and safety:\n\n"
        "The experience of gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender teens can be one of isolation, "
        "fear of prejudice and lack of peer or family support.\n\n"
        "Gay and lesbian youth have higher rates of suicide attempts. Up to 30% of gay and bisexual"
        " adolescent males say they have attempted suicide at least once. Some of the increased "
        "risk may be due to societal or family rejection of gay youth.\n\n"
        "Youth who report same-sex or both-sex romantic attraction are more likely to experience "
        "extreme forms of violence than youth who report heterosexual attraction.\n\n"
        "Homosexual and bisexual adolescents are at greater risk for STIs, substance abuse, "
        "unwanted pregnancies, suicide and earlier onset of heterosexual intercourse than their "
        "heterosexual peers.\n\n"
        "What Are The Details?\n\n"
        "Exploration with partners of both sexes is a natural part of growing up for many youth.\n\n"
        "How one’s sexual orientation is determined is unknown. It develops across a person's "
        "lifetime. Most experts agree that homosexuality is not caused by trauma, imitation of "
        "homosexual people, bad heterosexual experiences, sex role nonconformity, rape and sexual "
        "abuse.\n\n"
        "Sexual orientation is one component of a person’s identity. Sexual orientation is "
        "defined by a person’s feelings, not the type of sexual behavior he or she chooses to "
        "engage in.\n\n"
        "Coming out is a process of understanding and deciding not to hide one’s sexual "
        "orientation.\n\n"
        "A transgendered person is someone whose gender identity (someone’s internal sense of "
        "their gender) differs from the traditional expectations for their physical sex. They may "
        "be gay, straight, or bisexual.\n\n"
        "Homophobia—an intense or irrational fear or hatred of gays and lesbians—may make it very"
        " difficult for gay teens to feel safe, to express their feelings or to seek help.\n\n"
        "What Can I Do?\n\n"
        "If you are a parent who thinks your son or daughter is dealing with issues about their "
        "sexual orientation, there are groups and resources that can help.\n\n"
        "Find out about peer support groups for gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender teens, that "
        "are facilitated by trained adults. These groups can help teens cope with isolation and "
        "fears and help prevent high-risk behaviors. Make sure the schools in your area enforce "
        "policies to protect all students from verbal and physical harassment and abuse by other "
        "students and staff.\n\n"
        "What Do Teens Need From Me?\n\n"
        "Be aware of your own biases and prejudices about this topic before you talk with a young "
        "person.\n\n"
        "Make sure teens know that no one has the right to harass, threaten or hurt them because of"
        " their sexual orientation or gender identity. They need to tell a trusted adult if this "
        "ever happens.\n\n"
        "Gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender youth need to know that they are not alone, and "
        "that they are loved, accepted and valued.\n\n"
        "Teens don’t have to come out if they don’t feel ready or safe.\n\n"
        "Provide accurate information about sexual orientation to dispel stereotypes about gay, "
        "lesbian and bisexual sexuality.\n\n"
        "All young people need information that will help them protect their sexual health. Be "
        "prepared with accurate information to help teens understand their bodies and manage their "
        "feelings. Adults can help teens develop:\n\n"
        "Communication skills so they can talk with partners, friends and family members.\n\n"
        "Self-esteem to cope with homophobia and guard against peer pressures and engaging in "
        "sexual activity before they are ready.\n\n
        "A network of supportive friends, family, and professionals so they are loved and protected."
    </string>

    <string name="menuToday">Today</string>
    <string name="menuCalendar">Calendar</string>
    <string name="menuTopics">Topics</string>
    <string name="menuSettings">Settings</string>
    <string name="menuFeedback">Feedback</string>

    <string name="topicMenuSex">Gender and Sexuality</string>
    <string name="topicMenuDrugs">Drugs</string>
    <string name="topicMenuRel">Healthy Relationships</string>
    <string name="topicMenuBully">Bullying</string>
</resources>
